Guide to the Louise Morgan and Otto Theis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1917-65; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - Bowes-Lyon, Freda: drawings, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 462)
  - Bowes-Lyon, Lilian
    - Clippings, ca. 1940s (Box 21, Folder 463)
    - Correspondence about, 1943-50 (Box 21, Folder 464)
    - Photographs, 1949-58 (Box 21, Folder 465)
    - Poems, ca. 1940s (Box 21, Folder 466)
      See also: Box 13, folder 266
  - Bowes-Lyon family: clippings, 1948, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 467)
  - Boyde, H. C., 1946-49 (Box 21, Folder 468)
  - Brewer, Jocelyn, 1965 Jun (Box 21, Folder 469)
  - Brodribb, Conant: poems, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 470)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 930
  - Brown, F. J.: "The Lament for the, 1942 Oct 11 (Box 21, Folder 471)
  - Makers"
  - Bryher, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 472)
  - Cameron, Arthur
    - Man With a Hammer, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 473)
    - Poems, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 474)
    - Short stories, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 475)
  - Cameron, William
    - Business correspondence, 1938-40 (Box 22, Folder 476)
    - Clippings, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 477)
    - Hooky Jack's Monkeys, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 478)
    - Legal and financial papers, 1937-38 (Box 22, Folder 479)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 480)
      See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 931
  - Carr family, ca. 1940s (Box 22, Folder 481)
  - Chanel, Coco: business correspondence, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 482)
  - Chesterton, G. K., 1932 Apr 14 (Box 22, Folder 483)
  - Chi'en, Hsiao: Etching of a Tormented Age, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 484)
  - Church, Richard
    - Articles, 1953, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 485)
    - Psalms Written for a Time of War, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 486)
  - Civil Liaison, ca. 1940 (Box 22, Folder 487)
  - Clay, Enid: poems, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 488)
  - Clifford, Camille, 1934 Apr 30 (Box 22, Folder 489)
  - Cockerell, Douglas: Codex Sinaiticus, ? Apr 8 (Box 22, Folder 490)
  - Cooper, A. C.: photograph, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 491)
  - Cronin, A. J., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 492)
  - Culliman Diamond (Box 22, Folder 493)
  - Dane, Estrid, ca. 1940s (Box 22, Folder 494)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 932
  - Davies, Edwin: poems, 1947 Mar (Box 22, Folder 495)
  - De Courcy, Kenneth, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 496)
  - Deghy, Guy Stephan, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 497)
  - Donoghue, Steve: article, 1927 Apr 19 (Box 22, Folder 498)
  - Douglas, C. H.: obituary, 1952 Oct 1 (Box 22, Folder 499)
  - Douglas, Norman: clipping, 1953 Aug 28 (Box 22, Folder 500)
  - Douglas, Richard C.: "Our Coloured Brethern in Arms", n.d. (Box 22, Folder 501)
  - Edmonds, Jim: poems, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 502)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 933
  - Ellerman, John Reeves, Sir: Dictionary of National Biography entry, 1945-46 (Box 22, Folder 503)
  - Ellerman family: clippings, 1930s (Box 22, Folder 504)
  - Eliot, T. S., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 505)
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic, 1937 Apr 30 (Box 22, Folder 506)
  - Scientists: correspondence
  - Essex, County of, 1951, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 507)
  - Farjeon, Eleanor, 1958, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 508)
  - Freud, Anna, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Frewen, Oswald: clippings, 1958, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 510)
    See also: Box 17, folder 364
  - Garvin, J. L., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Garvin, Viola
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 935
  - Gibbings, Robert: obituary, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 512)
  - Godwin, Catherina: short stories, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Gollancz, Victor, 1933, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 514)
  - Gordine, Dora, 1930s-1940s (Box 22, Folder 515)
  - Gould, Frederick, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 516)
  - Grahame, Kenneth, 1938, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 517)
  - Griffith, Sanford: article, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 518)
  - Griffiths, H. Ernest: articles, 1947-48 (Box 23, Folder 519)
  - H.D.: clippings, 1944, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 520)
  - Hampstead Nursery: monthly reports, 1941-45 (Box 23, Folder 521-25)
    See also: Box 8, folders 162-63; Box 22, folder 509
  - Holtby, Winifred: article, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 526)
  - Holtzmann, Fanny
    - Addresses about Zionism and Palestine, 1946, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 527)
    - Correspondence with Francis Williams, 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 528-29)
    - Letter about war debts, 1945 Dec 20 (Box 23, Folder 530)
    - Notes on Pamela Clatworthy, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 531)
      See also: Box 6, folder 104; Box 18, folder 398
    - Photographs and clippings, 1950s (Box 23, Folder 532)
  - Hopkinson, Thomas: clippings, 1955, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Horder, Thomas, Lord: clippings, 1955, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 534)
  - Institute of Child Health: correspondence, 1951 Jan 9 (Box 23, Folder 535)
  - International Anti-Fascist Solidarity: correspondence, 1938 Apr 8 (Box 23, Folder 536)
    See also: Box 12, folders 250-52
  - International Brigaders Association: correspondence, 1943 Jun 15 (Box 23, Folder 537)
  - International Working Men's Association, First, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 538)
  - Jameson, Storm: "Somewhere to Live--A Long Search", 1956 Feb 25 (Box 24, Folder 539)
  - Keith, Arthur, Sir, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 540)
  - Kennedy, Margaret, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 541)
  - Kerr, John Graham, Sir
    - Articles, 1935, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 542)
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 543)
  - Kolisko, L., 1941, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 544)
  - Lamude, F. J., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 545)
  - Leslie, Shane, 1958, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 546)
  - London, 1940s-50s (Box 24, Folder 547)
  - Lowenfeld, Margaret, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 548)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 936
  - Lynd, Sylvia: "A Comment" (Box 24, Folder 549)
  - Macaulay, Rose: clipping, 1961 Oct 26 (Box 24, Folder 550)
  - McAlmon, Robert: typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 551)
  - Mannin, Ethel, 1937, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 552)
  - Mansel, Freda: clipping, 1935 Aug 15 (Box 24, Folder 553)
  - Markham, Violet: obituary, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 554)
  - Marshall, Geoff N.: articles, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 555)
  - Masefield, John
    - Biographical information, 1931, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 556)
    - Clippings, 1959-63 (Box 24, Folder 557)
    - Poems, 1956, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 558)
  - Montgomery, Bernard Law, Viscount, 1959 Jan 4 (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Morgan, Louise, 1922-46 (Box 24, Folder 560)
  - Morgan, Rita: Top Floor, 1948, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 561)
  - National Association of Girls Clubs: correspondence, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 562)
  - National Children Adoption Association: correspondence, 1945-46 (Box 24, Folder 563)
  - National Joint Committee for Spanish Relief: correspondence, 1944 Oct 2 (Box 24, Folder 564)
  - Neill, A. S.: articles, 1951, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Newman, Augustus Charles, Lt. Col., 1945 Jun 19 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Nicholas L. Brown: correspondence, 1917-24 (Box 24, Folder 567-68)
  - Nutrition (Box 24, Folder 569-70)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam: "The Oar", 1927 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Oldenfield, Josiah: clippings, 1946, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 572)
  - O'Sullivan, Vincent, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 573)
  - Oved, Mosheh
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 574)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 575)
  - Padmore, George
    - Clippings about colonialism, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 576)
    - Correspondence with publishers, 1942, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 577)
    - How Britain Rules Africa, 1935, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 578)
  - Palmer, Herbert Edward
    - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 579)
    - Other works, 1933, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 580)
    - Poems, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 581)
  - Pant, Apa B., Rajda of Aundh: (Box 25, Folder 582)
  - "A Short Note on Surya Namaskars --A Yoga Exercise"
  - Peculiar People, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 583)
  - Pember, Evelyn, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 584)
  - Pennyman, Ruth, 1948 May (Box 25, Folder 585)
  - Pioneer Health Center
    - Clippings, 1940s-50s (Box 25, Folder 586)
    - Correspondence, 1943-49 (Box 25, Folder 587)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 588)
    - Photographs, ca. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 589)
  - Plomer, William: clippings, 1958, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 590)
  - Pollock, Benjamin, 1937, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 591)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 937
  - Progressive Film Institute: correspondence, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 592)
  - Purdom, C. B.: clipping, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 593)
  - Quiller-Couch, Arthur, Sir, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 594)
  - Rankin, Rhondda: articles (Box 25, Folder 595)
  - Reynolds, Reginald, 1958, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 596)
  - Richardson, Dorothy
    - Articles about, 1931-59 (Box 25, Folder 597)
    - Correspondence about, 1958-59 (Box 25, Folder 598)
    - Morgan's copies of correspondence (Box 25, Folder 599)
    - Morgan's notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 600)
  - Riddell, Pamela: "The Yellow Kimona", n.d. (Box 25, Folder 601)
  - Roberts, John: clipping, 1958 Jan 25 (Box 25, Folder 602)
  - Robertson, W. Graham: article, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 603)
  - Robinson, E. A., n.d. (Box 25, Folder 604)
  - Russell, Alys: obituary, 1950 Sep 26 (Box 25, Folder 605)
  - Sanderson, Averil, Lady (Box 25, Folder 606)
  - Schulberg family, 1949, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 607)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 608)
  - Sea battles, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 609)
  - Sea voyages, 1938,1942 (Box 26, Folder 610)
  - Selincourt, Anne de, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 611)
  - Sharp, Clifford: Cecil Rhodes, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 612)
  - Shaw, G. B., 1945-62 (Box 26, Folder 613)
  - Sheridan, Claire, 1935-58 (Box 26, Folder 614)
  - Silicosis: News Chronicle article, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 615)
  - Soal, S. G.: clipping, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 616)
  - Social Security League: correspondence, 1944 Jul 13 (Box 26, Folder 617)
  - Somerville, Mary: clippings, 1955, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 618)
  - Squire, J. C., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 619)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1951 May 14 (Box 26, Folder 620)
  - Strachan, W. J.: "Chastel's Illustrations for 'Le Bestiaire'"
    See: Oversize, Box 39, folder 938
  - Strudwick, Sheppard, Jr., 1949, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 621)
  - Suffolk, Earl of, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 622)
  - Summerhill School, 1949-50 (Box 26, Folder 623)
    See also: Box 13, folder 272
  - Sutherland, Millicent (Hawes), Duchess of (Box 26, Folder 624)
  - Sutton, Eric, 1949, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 625)
  - Swing, Betty, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 626)
  - Swing, Raymond
    - Articles, 1936, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 627)
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 628)
    - Manuscripts and correspondence, ca. 1935 (Box 26, Folder 629)
  - Swinnerton, Frank: "A.B.s Last Journal", ca. 1933 (Box 26, Folder 630)
  - Theis, Otto
    - Financial papers, 1921-26 (Box 26, Folder 631)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 632)
  - Theis, Sophia, 1923 (Box 26, Folder 633)
  - Tomlinson, H. M., 1932, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 634)
  - Trade union movement: correspondence, 1933 Jun 16 (Box 26, Folder 635)
  - Traubel, Horace, 1912 Nov 25 (Box 26, Folder 636)
  - Trimmer, Sarah, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 637)
  - Vale, Edmund, 1933 Nov (Box 26, Folder 638)
  - Vaughan, Janet: clippings, 1940s-50s (Box 26, Folder 639)
  - Walker, Ethel, ca. 1945 (Box 26, Folder 640)
  - Wallace, Ethel, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 641)
  - Wedgwood Company: correspondence, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 642)
  - Wells, H. G., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 643)
  - West, Rebecca, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 644)
  - Wilkinson, Mona: poems, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 645)
  - Women's organizations: correspondence, 1932, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 646)
  - Woolf, Leonard, 1961 Jan (Box 26, Folder 647)
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1931, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 648)
  - Young, A. P.: "Foothold in industry-- spiritual values in the workshop", 1950 Aug 31 (Box 26, Folder 649)
  - Young, Alan: poems, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 650)
- Professional Papers, 1924-63; Series III; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series III, Professional Papers, fills Boxes 27-32 and is divided into four sections: Everyman, Outlook, Morgan Literary Papers, and Theis Literary Papers. The first two subseries are alphabetically arranged by subject, while the second two are arranged by section and then by subject. All correspondence files are chronologically arranged, except for "Readers' letters" which is only arranged by year.
  - EVERYMAN
    - Articles: "How Writers Work"
      - Frankau, Gilbert, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 651)
      - Macaulay, Rose, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 652)
      - Mottram, R. H., n.d. (Box 27, Folder 653)
      - Swinnerton, Frank, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 654)
    - Business correspondence, 1931-33 (Box 27, Folder 655-58)
    - Business journal, [1933?] (Box 27, Folder 659)
    - History, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 660)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 661)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 662)
  - OUTLOOK
    - Business Correspondence
      - Morgan, Louise, 1928 Jun (Box 27, Folder 663)
      - Theis, Otto, 1925, 1928 (Box 27, Folder 664-66)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 667)
  - MORGAN LITERARY PAPERS
    All of the material relates to Morgan's work Inside Yourself (1954), except for the last folders in the section.
    - Research Correspondence
      - Alexander, F. M.
        - Morgan, Louise, 1952-57 (Box 27, Folder 668-72)
        - Press, 1950-51 (Box 27, Folder 673-74)
        - Press, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 675)
      - BBC (Box 28, Folder 676)
      - Binkley, Goddard, 1957-60 (Box 28, Folder 677)
      - Carrington, Walter, 1954-63 (Box 28, Folder 678-82)
      - Douglas, Mungo
        - Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 28, Folder 683)
        - Printed works, 1937-54 (Box 28, Folder 684)
          See also: Box 29, folders 720-21
      - Feltner, George, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 685)
      - Jones, Frank P., 1962 (Box 28, Folder 686)
      - MacDonald, Patrick J., 1957 (Box 28, Folder 687)
      - Neil, Charles
        - Correspondence, 1952-57 (Box 28, Folder 688)
        - Printed works, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 689)
      - Skinner, John, 1952-57 (Box 28, Folder 690)
      - Spivey, Ludd M., 1954-56 (Box 28, Folder 691)
    - Correspondence Concerning Publication
      - American publication, 1954-62, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 692-96)
      - Argument with Lord Thomas Horder, 1952-54 (Box 28, Folder 697)
        See also: Box 10, folder 205
      - British publication, 1952-60 (Box 28, Folder 698-700)
      - Fan Mail, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 701-02)
        See also: Box 14, folder 316
      - Fan Mail, 1955-64, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 703-11)
      - General, 1950-61 (Box 29, Folder 712-14)
      - News Chronicle, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 715)
    - Research and Background Material
      - Draft pages, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 716)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 717)
      - Newspaper clippings about posture and health, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 718)
      - Notes, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 719)
      - Other printed works, 1950s-60s (Box 29, Folder 720-21)
        See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 939; Box 28, folders 684, 689
      - Photographs, 1954, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 722)
      - Printed works on posture and health, 1950s-60s (Box 29, Folder 723)
      - Printed works on posture and health, 1950s-60s (Box 30, Folder 724)
      - Printed works by F. M. Alexander, 1906-09 (Box 30, Folder 725)
      - Shooting script: "Education--A New Basis--The F.M. Alexander Technique", 1962 (Box 30, Folder 726)
    - Other Writings
      - "The New World of the Motor Car", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 727)
  - THEIS LITERARY PAPERS
    All of the material in this subseries relates to Theis's work reviewing books, except for the last section, called Other Papers. Book Reviews are arranged alphabetically by author, and by title when the author is unknown. There is some correspondence and an occasional manuscript filed with the reviews.
    - Correspondence
      - "B-H" general, 1930-37 (Box 30, Folder 728)
      - Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1930-36 (Box 30, Folder 729)
      - "M" general, 1936, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 730)
      - "S" general, 1929, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 731)
      - Simpkin Marshall Ltd., 1940 (Box 30, Folder 732)
      - "T-W" general, 1930-37 (Box 30, Folder 733)
    - Book Reviews
      - Adler - Ammers-Küller, 1931-37 (Box 30, Folder 734)
      - Amorim - Aschner, 1930-39 (Box 30, Folder 735)
      - Baker - Blake, 1930-36 (Box 30, Folder 736)
      - Bloch - Braun-Bessin, 1930-40 (Box 30, Folder 737)
      - Brentano - Butler, 1929-40 (Box 30, Folder 738)
      - Calderon - Choromanski, 1930-40 (Box 30, Folder 739)
      - Ciliga - Coudray, 1931-47 (Box 30, Folder 740)
      - Cunard, Nancy, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 741)
      - Dachau - Demtschinsky, 1931-40 (Box 30, Folder 742)
      - Dibelius - Dymow, 1930-40 (Box 30, Folder 743)
      - Ebermayer, Erich, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 744)
      - Edib, Halide, ca. 1933 (Box 30, Folder 745)
      - Elert - Elster, 1934, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 746)
      - The Enchanted Circle - Ewer, 1930-39 (Box 30, Folder 747)
      - Fabricius - Frank, 1930-40 (Box 30, Folder 748)
      - Frank-Ruta - Fürst Bülow und der Kaiser, 1930-39 (Box 30, Folder 749)
      - Gäfgen - Grenen, 1930-36 (Box 30, Folder 750)
      - Grimm - Grühl, 1931-36 (Box 31, Folder 751)
      - Gudmundsson - Gurney, 1929-40 (Box 31, Folder 752)
      - Hahn - Harten, 1935-37 (Box 31, Folder 753)
      - Hartenstein - Hitler, 1930-39 (Box 31, Folder 754)
      - Hoellriegel - Hoffmann-Harnisch, 1933, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 755)
      - Holland, Katrin (Box 31, Folder 756)
      - Hollander - Huna, 1930-36 (Box 31, Folder 757)
      - Ihoring - Jelnsich, 1934-38 (Box 31, Folder 758)
      - Kästner, Erich, 1924-38 (Box 31, Folder 759)
      - Kahan - Karpov, 1930-39 (Box 31, Folder 760)
      - Kaus, Gina, 1930, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 761)
      - Kettel - Kiefer, 1930-37 (Box 31, Folder 762)
      - Kiel - Kretschmayer, 1931-36 (Box 31, Folder 763)
      - Krieger - Kyber, 1931-36 (Box 31, Folder 764)
      - La Born - Larsen, 1936-39 (Box 31, Folder 765)
      - Lauterbach - Lernet-Holenia, 1933-38 (Box 31, Folder 766)
      - Lesk - Lucka, 1930-38 (Box 31, Folder 767)
      - Maass, Joachim, 1935 Dec 8 (Box 31, Folder 768)
      - McAlmon, Robert, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 769)
      - Mackin - Mantler, 1931-38 (Box 31, Folder 770)
      - Marai - Mills-Young, 1934-38 (Box 31, Folder 771)
      - Monnickendam - Munkepunke, 1937-40 (Box 31, Folder 772)
      - Nabokov - Sirin - Noyes, 1930-36 (Box 31, Folder 773)
      - Olden - Owen, 1930-38 (Box 31, Folder 774)
      - Pauli - Pollatscher, 1936-39 (Box 31, Folder 775)
      - Pückler - Pulay, 1934-39 (Box 32, Folder 776)
      - Rachmanowa - Ringelnatz, 1931-39 (Box 32, Folder 777)
      - Robakidse - Roubé-Jansky, 1930-36 (Box 32, Folder 778)
      - Rowan - Ruir, 1932-39 (Box 32, Folder 779)
      - Saager - Sachs, 1930, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 780)
      - Salomon, Ernst von, 1932-36 (Box 32, Folder 781)
      - Salten - Schalit, 1930-39 (Box 32, Folder 782)
      - Schaper - Seibert, 1931-38 (Box 32, Folder 783)
      - Seyd - Smirnowa, 1930-36 (Box 32, Folder 784)
      - Smith, Dorothy, 1934, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 785)
      - Snell - Stecher, 1937-39 (Box 32, Folder 786)
      - Steiner - Svensson, 1931-40 (Box 32, Folder 787)
      - Tacitus Revisited - Towers, 1930-40 (Box 32, Folder 788)
      - Trebitsch - Troeltsch, 1930-38 (Box 32, Folder 789)
      - Ullrich - Urbanitzky, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 790)
      - Vegesack - Vuocijoki, 1930-37 (Box 32, Folder 791)
      - Wagenführ - Winder, 1931-39 (Box 32, Folder 792)
      - Winsloe - Wynn, 1931-40 (Box 32, Folder 793)
      - Zarek - Zweig, 1932-39 (Box 32, Folder 794)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 795)
        See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 940
    - Other Papers
      - Writings
        - Review of Cocteau, Jean: A call to order (Le rappel à l'ordre), typescript, unsigned, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 796)
        - "Émile Verhaeren,": essay, manuscript, with letter (incomplete?) to, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 797)
      - Literary Material
        - Employment correspondence, 1928, 1932 (Box 32, Folder 798)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 799)
- Evelyn Scott Papers, 1921-63; Series IV; 1.5; (3 boxes)
  Series IV, Evelyn Scott Papers, fills Boxes 33-35. It is divided into two subseries: Scott Correspondence and Related Correspondence and Papers. All the letters are to Louise and Otto Theis, except Scott's letters to Owen Merton (folder 800-01). There are also some letters from the Theises. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name and then chronologically.
  - SCOTT CORRESPONDENCE
    - Merton, Owen, 1925, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 800-01)
    - Morgan, Louise, 1921-25 (Box 33, Folder 802-10)
    - Theis, Otto
    - Morgan, Louise, 1926-63 (Box 34, Folder 811-27)
    - Theis, Otto
  - RELATED CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS
    - Merton, Owen, 1923-26 (Box 34, Folder 828-30)
    - Metcalfe, John
      - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 831-39)
      - Book review, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 840)
    - Morgan, Louise, 1920s, 1960s (Box 35, Folder 841)
    - Theis, Otto
    - Other correspondents, 1923-31 (Box 35, Folder 842)
      See also: Box 1, folder 16; Box 6-7, folders 126-29; Box 7, folder 132
    - Scott, Cyril
      - Business correspondence regarding publication of Siren, 1925 (Box 35, Folder 843)
      - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 844-49)
      - Sketchbook, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 850)
      - Undated and miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 851)
    - Scott, Elsa, 1925, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 852)
- Nancy Cunard Papers, 1925-62; Series V; 1.5; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Nancy Cunard Papers, fills Boxes 36-38. The correspondence is divided into two subseries: Cunard Correspondence and Related Correspondence and Papers. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name and then chronologically. Material relating to a specific individual is filed with the correspondence. Poems are arranged alphabetically by title, with untitled poems grouped at the end.
  - CUNARD CORRESPONDENCE
    - Morgan, Louise, 1925-52 (Box 36, Folder 853-77)
    - Theis, Otto
      See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 941-43
    - Morgan, Louise, 1953-62 (Box 37, Folder 878-98)
    - Theis, Otto
    - Morgan, Louise, 1963-65, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 899-902)
    - Theis, Otto
  - RELATED CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS
    - Banting, John, 1938-62, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 903-04)
    - Crowder, Henry, 1931, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 905)
    - Morgan, Louise
      - Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 906-08)
      - Notes, 1950s-60s (Box 38, Folder 909-10)
    - Other correspondents (Box 38, Folder 911)
      See also: Box 6, folder 109-10; Box 9, folder 171; Box 15, folders 323-28; Box 17, folder 373; Box 19, folder 424
      Includes: Roger Senhouse
  - POEMS
    - "A-I" general, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 912)
    - "L-M" general, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 913)
    - "R" general, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 914)
    - "S, V" general, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 915)
    - Written in Spain, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 916)
    - Written for Morgan and Theis (Box 38, Folder 917)
    - Untitled, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 918)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - L'Age d'Or, ca. 1930 (Box 38, Folder 919)
    - Blacks, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 920)
    - Hours Press, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 921)
    - Spanish Civil War/Fascism, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 922)
  - ADDITIONAL MATERIAL
    - See also: Box 30, folder 741, for material concerning Colour and Negro.
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 923)
        See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 944
      - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 924)
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 925)
- Oversize, 1907-64; 1.75; (1 box)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series I, II, III, and V, in a parallel arrangement.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Easterbrook, Laurence, 1946 Feb 2 (Box 39, Folder 926)
    - Edib, Halide, 1925 Nov 12 (Box 39, Folder 927)
    - Evans, Donald, [1907 Oct 10] (Box 39, Folder 928)
    - Wied, K., ca. 1936 (Box 39, Folder 929)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Brodribb, Conant: poems, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 930)
    - Cameron, William: misc., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 931)
    - Dane, Estrid, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 932)
    - Edmonds, Jim: poems, 1941 Mar 15 (Box 39, Folder 933)